Guide to the Amos Sheffield Chesebrough Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Amos Sheffield Chesebrough papers
1839-1904
MS 888
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
Sermons, speeches, diaries, and commonplace books of Amos Sheffield Chesebrough and four letters from Joseph Hopkins Twichell. The diaries were kept during a trip to Europe in 1857 in which Cheesebrough visited London, Heidelberg and other German cities. The sermons, which make up the major portion of the papers, span the period when he was pastor in churches in Chester, Glastonbury, Vernon and Durham, Connecticut.
Chesebrough, Amos S. (Amos Sheffield), 1813-1905
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Frank J. Sprague, 1943-1944.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Amos S. Chesebrough: from 1835-1837 served as principal of two academies in Massachusetts; from 1841-1853 served as pastor of Congregational Church in Chester, Ct.; from 1853-1857 assisted in his father's mercantile business and occasionally preached; from 1858-1868 pastor of First Church in Glastonbury, Ct.; from 1871-1876 pastor of church in Vernon, Ct.; pastor of First Church of Durham, Ct., 1876-.
Scope and Contents
Sermons, speeches, diaries, and commonplace books of Amos Sheffield Chesebrough and four letters from Joseph Hopkins Twichell. The diaries were kept during a trip to Europe in 1857 in which Chesebrough visited London, Heidelberg and other German cities. The sermons, which make up the major portion of the papers, span the period when he was pastor in churches in Chester, Glastonbury, Vernon and Durham, Connecticut.
Congregational churches -- Connecticut; Europe -- Description and travel; Commonplace books; Diaries; Sermons; Clergy; Chesebrough, Amos S. (Amos Sheffield), 1813-1905; Twichell, Joseph Hopkins, 1838-1918
- Inventory
  - Twichell, Joseph Hopkins (1838-1918): 4 ALS to Amos S. Chesebrough, 1901-1904 (Box 1)
  - Sermons (by date of first delivery), 1839-1891 (Box 1)
  - Addresses
    - "The Saybrook Confession of Faith of 1708" (Middlesex Assocation), 1888 (Box 1)
    - "Half Century Talk" (Chester), 1891 (Box 1)
    - "Reminiscences, 1841-1853" (Middlesex Assoc.), 1900 (Box 1)
    - "Greeting", undated (Box 1)
    - "Hints on Christian Education: First Paper", undated (Box 1)
    - "Scepticism", undated (Box 1)
  - "Scriptures relative to Children" (transcripts), undated (Box 1)
  - Diaries (principally the outgoing voyage, London, Heidelberg, other German cities), 1857 (Box 1)
  - Diary (principally London and the voyage home) and passports, 1857 (Box 2)
  - Commonplace books, undated (Box 2)